[{"id": "5fe768aaeec85e375820b2a4", "question": "What country once had a banknote that featured a woman riding a shark?", "answer": "Cook Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e5d", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Daffy Duck?", "answer": "Mel Blanc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dac", "question": "What bassist's romance with Astrid Kirchherr is the subject of the film \"Backbeat\"?", "answer": "Stu Sutcliffe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f20", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Arnie Cunningham?", "answer": "Christine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea45cdff048f679a45ab99", "question": "If nitrous oxide is added to an engine, what will the effect be?", "answer": "Adds more oxygen to the engine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f5649133a95c66dc4fe74f", "question": "Roman Polanski directed which 1974 film starring Jack Nicholson?", "answer": "Chinatown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c3", "question": "The Chevy model known as the Camaro was originally intended to be called what?", "answer": "Panther", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e94a77ccba3ffe45786d6", "question": "What common term is used to describe a length of 9 inches?", "answer": "A span", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ad", "question": "Who played the teenage prostitute in the 1976 film \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "Jodie Foster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a6", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Greece?", "answer": "Olympus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad03", "question": "What archaeological site is known as the Lost City of the Incas?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c027", "question": "What is \"military commander\" in Japanese?", "answer": "Shogun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac4", "question": "What early rock pioneer once told an unresponsive audience, \"I hope you all get heart attacks\"?", "answer": "Jerry Lee Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec877fec223966ae8f8815", "question": "Which rock legend's real name is William Bailey?", "answer": "Axl Rose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a521", "question": "Lesotho is landlocked by which country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1eb", "question": "What two alcohols are used to make a Sazerac cocktail?", "answer": "Cognac, or rye, and absinthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69b2420565ad31a57c75c", "question": "Which World War II battle saw the greatest number of tanks used in world history?", "answer": "The Battle of Kursk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015ea64fe83fe1f2a824bf0", "question": "When was the flush toilet invented?", "answer": "The first modern flushable toilet was described in 1596 by Sir John Harington, the godson of Queen Elizabeth I.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c28e", "question": "What are you if you are myopic?", "answer": "Near-sighted", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a162", "question": "Kappelkoff is the real surname of which actress?", "answer": "Doris Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe698ff20565ad31a57c73e", "question": "The first-ever ticker-tape parade was thrown in celebration of what event?", "answer": "The dedication of the Statue of Liberty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931c", "question": "In the \"Back to the Future\", what speed did the DeLorean have to reach to activate the flux capacitor?", "answer": "88 miles per hour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb359eb2627b8fe95581be6", "question": "What nickname is printed on the official Wilson NFL football?", "answer": "The Duke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008df8cf842fa4c4ba96ae", "question": "In the world of wine, what does \"Chambre\" mean?", "answer": "Serve at room temperature", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87b", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Nathan Road\"?", "answer": "Hong Kong", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0e327fcbed638185eaa21", "question": "Which South American country is known as the \"Land of Poets\"?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94c", "question": "The name of which martial art means \"gentle way\"?", "answer": "Judo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df2", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"commando\"?", "answer": "Afrikaans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6018bc84d96d05b23b281656", "question": "Who captured and murdered the Inca Emperor Atahualpa?", "answer": "Francisco Pizarro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be7", "question": "Who are the creators of the TV show \"Seinfeld\"?", "answer": "Larry David and Jerry Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a59e", "question": "In what mountains is Camp David?", "answer": "Appalachian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c44d", "question": "How many chromosomes does an elephant have?", "answer": "56", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c970", "question": "What is an organism called that lives on or in a host animal?", "answer": "Parasite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a798", "question": "What five countries border Peru?", "answer": "Colombia, Ecuador, Brazil, Bolivia and Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a119", "question": "Which classic Hollywood western is based on the film \"Seven Samurai\"?", "answer": "The Magnificent Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339630", "question": "Which TV show's theme song starts with the words \"Come and knock on my door...\"?", "answer": "Three's Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f86", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in Children of a Lesser God?", "answer": "Marlee Matlin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338931", "question": "What is the highest musical note on a standard 88-key piano?", "answer": "C8", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1cd", "question": "Creme de Menthe, fresh cream and what other ingredient are combined to make a Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Creme de Cacao", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c5", "question": "What year marked the appearance of Doc Savage?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a318", "question": "Which pop duo consisted of Fab Morvan and Rob Pilatus?", "answer": "Milli Vanilli", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e3", "question": "At what age did Buffalo Bill become a rider for the Pony Express?", "answer": "14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982c", "question": "What town was the setting of The Andy Griffith Show?", "answer": "Mayberry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba7", "question": "What museum, designed by Frank Lloyd Wright, was opened in 1959?", "answer": "Guggenheim Museum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5eb73c6b5e259d7869087331", "question": "Who was the designer of the Lincoln penny coin?", "answer": "Victor David Brenner", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a6", "question": "What gate does the three-headed dog Cerberus guard?", "answer": "The gates to the Underworld", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b44", "question": "What name brand condiment is mentioned in the Jimmy Buffet song \"Cheeseburger in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Heinz 57", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe37a6d0ada16518afdc059", "question": "How many concentration camps did Nazi Germany operate in Occupied Poland?", "answer": "457", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8e", "question": "What was the name of Paul McCartney's backup group from 1971 to 1981?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e0", "question": "\"Mork & Mindy\" was a spin-off of what TV show?", "answer": "Happy Days", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a190", "question": "Paul Stanley is the co-singer for which Rock-N-Roll band?", "answer": "Kiss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e9", "question": "What group's 1979 debut album was entitled \"Reproduction\"?", "answer": "Human League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef3", "question": "Which member of \"the Rat Pack\" was married to a Kennedy?", "answer": "Peter Lawford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c96a", "question": "What sort of animal is a fennec?", "answer": "A fox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d11a084fea7fe947a22293", "question": "What is the fear of politicians known as?", "answer": "Politicophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8e", "question": "What is James Bowie reported to have dropped into a well at the Alamo?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb8", "question": "What was the home US state of Alan Alda's characters in both \"M*A*S*H\" and \"The Aviator\"?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c5", "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian province of Manitoba?", "answer": "Winnipeg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2a", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Lagaan\"?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26d", "question": "What ship carried Captain Cook to Australia?", "answer": "Endeavour", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d3", "question": "What was the name of the Ewing's ranch on the TV series \"Dallas\"?", "answer": "Southfork", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66a49a5bfecdd737e0882", "question": "What was Nike's original name?", "answer": "Blue Ribbon Sports", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb0", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Juliet\", was Romeo a Capulet or a Montague?", "answer": "Montague", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ad", "question": "What was the Asian nation of Myanmar known as prior to 1989?", "answer": "Burma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d25", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Over the Top\"?", "answer": "Arm wrestling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f9", "question": "What is the second smallest country in the world?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca09", "question": "Which chemical has the atomic number one?\u00a0", "answer": "Hydrogen\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a620", "question": "What aquifer provides water for Nebraska, Kansas and Oklahoma?", "answer": "Ogallala aquifer", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0c", "question": "What author created the character of Roderick Alleyn?", "answer": "Ngaio Marsh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c343", "question": "What is the sound a camel makes called?", "answer": "Nuzzing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f5662b33a95c66dc4fe760", "question": "Mentu is the Egyptian god of what?", "answer": "War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95e", "question": "\"Panther Cap\", \"Stinkhorn\" and \"Penny Bun\" are all types of what?", "answer": "Fungi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afac", "question": "What was Sunday, January 30th 1972, generally remembered as in Ireland?", "answer": "Bloody Sunday", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ed", "question": "What is a single piece of coiled DNA is known as?", "answer": "Chromosome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee3", "question": "What is the front of a saddle called?", "answer": "Pommel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95b1bc55722f97b22684de", "question": "What year did the Original Dungeons and Dragons box set by Gary Gygax and Dave Arneson debut?", "answer": "1974", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133952c", "question": "What John Wayne film, set during the Civil War, was based on a true story?", "answer": "The Horse Soldiers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cda00e347d002c297e4d1", "question": "Who was James Stewart's female co-start in Hitchcock's \"Rear Window\"?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cb70e99f96e155acab35d3a", "question": "Who painted \"The Starry Night\"?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc8c2ec223966ae8f8892", "question": "What was the name of the long-standing official Nintendo strategy magazine?", "answer": "\"Nintendo Power\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99e", "question": "What well known drug comes from the cinchona tree?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a58f", "question": "What U.S. state has the longest freshwater shoreline?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5941260abab1e6f9796f1b57", "question": "In Greek mythology, \"Sirens\" were represented as a combination of woman and what animal?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58bb338ce368446ca7bd6845", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion looking for?", "answer": "Courage\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b591", "question": "What does the abbreviation MBA stand for in the MBA master's degree designation?", "answer": "Master of Business Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdafeec223966ae8f88ef", "question": "What is the life span of a replicant in \"Blade Runner\"?", "answer": "Four years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d6", "question": "Who was the first president of the Academy of Motion of Picture Arts and Sciences?", "answer": "Douglas Fairbanks Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d474e4f8e329de4f8778a1", "question": "The \"Associated Powers\" was the original proposed name of what organization?", "answer": "The United Nations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc8", "question": "What was the capital city of Portugal between the years 1808 and 1821?", "answer": "Rio de Janeiro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394dd", "question": "What kind of animals are \"Pinky and the Brain\"?", "answer": "Lab mice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c655", "question": "What is the worlds fastest dog?", "answer": "The Greyhound", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a98b", "question": "What city named its airport after Jomo Kenyatta?", "answer": "Nairobi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a396", "question": "What is the official language of Papua New Guinea?", "answer": "English", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffcf11cf6db9ac4808d06", "question": "What is the largest desert in the U.S.?", "answer": "Great Basin Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4dcf306d333868d34d6fd", "question": "Who won four gold medals in the 1936 Olympics, infuriating Adolf Hitler?", "answer": "Jessie Owens", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ea", "question": "Who is the developer of the game series \"Gran Turismo\"?", "answer": "Polyphony Digital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8adf901dd7bf43be5e781", "question": "Pinto Colvig is better known as the original what?", "answer": "Bozo the clown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ceb", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Jaws\"?", "answer": "Peter Benchley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c06", "question": "Who wrote \"A History of the English-Speaking Peoples\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a488", "question": "William Mynors is the captain that discovered and named what island in 1643?", "answer": "Christmas Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca7", "question": "What musical talent does the Devil display in the song \"The Devil Went Down to Georgia\"?", "answer": "Fiddle playing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e759b24f84e0b9f9ffb8", "question": "Which Star Wars villain shares a voice with the narrator of the 1995 film \"Judge Dredd\"?", "answer": "Darth Vader", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a893", "question": "What city is home to the Shukhov Tower?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0bc", "question": "What pseudonym was Norma McCorvey given in a historic 1973 Supreme Court ruling?", "answer": "Jane Roe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde9", "question": "Shechita is the method of producing meat that is what?", "answer": "Kosher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b1", "question": "Which heroine comes from Amphipolis?", "answer": "Xena", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339591", "question": "What is outlawed in the town in the movie \"Footloose\"?", "answer": "Dancing and rock music", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ae", "question": "What did Leonard Nimoy need a new pair of every few days in the late 1960's?", "answer": "Ears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8d", "question": "What Christian sect observes its Sabbath on Saturday?", "answer": "Seventh-Day Adventists", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c208", "question": "What year was the UK an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1908", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e0", "question": "What type of creature is a copperhead?", "answer": "A snake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b0", "question": "Which music genre lilterally means \"new trend\" in Portuguese?", "answer": "Bossa Nova", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008dcacf4f3bc4a292f861b", "question": "How many times was Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. arrested?", "answer": "29 (Many of the charges against him were illegitimate and the result of widespread, systemic racism.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b25d", "question": "Which amendment to the US Constitution deals with presidential succession?", "answer": "Twenty fifth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1f", "question": "What two-sport athlete didn't speak in his early 1990's Nike commercials because of his bad stutter?", "answer": "Bo Jackson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95b05555722f97b22684dc", "question": "Who was the Hogwarts' headmaster right before Dumbledore?", "answer": "Armando Dippet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f8a", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Maria Full of Grace\"?", "answer": "Catalina Sandino Moreno", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdcefec223966ae8f88fa", "question": "Which Christmas song was the second piece of music broadcast on the radio?", "answer": "\"O Holy Night\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f0", "question": "What are the three traditional ingredients of shortbread cookies?", "answer": "Butter, flour and sugar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad08", "question": "What H-word means designing, displaying and describing coats of arms and badges?", "answer": "Heraldry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa71", "question": "Rioja wine comes from which country?", "answer": "Spain\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd86", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, King Ghidorah?", "answer": "Three-headed dragon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f24", "question": "What actor did Michael J. Fox replace as Marty McFly in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Eric Stolz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c044", "question": "What do you have if you suffer from podobromhidrosis?", "answer": "Smelly feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea40f3ff048f679a45ab6c", "question": "Who discovered that a moving magnet generates electric current known as electromagnetic induction?", "answer": "Michael Faraday", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a0f0cad1ec93f27df772", "question": "What do you ferment to make kombucha?", "answer": "Sweetened tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c62b86e0ae4aacefc17eee1", "question": "What was Studio Ghibli's highest grossing film?", "answer": "Spirited Away", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c770", "question": "What \"L\"-word is the name for the family of plants including the peanut and soybean?", "answer": "Legume", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ae", "question": "What name was given to textile workers who opposed modernisation during the 19th century?\u00a0", "answer": "Luddites\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad0b", "question": "Whose 1923 death made Calvin Coolidge US president?", "answer": "Warren Harding", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fc", "question": "Which word, taken from the French, translates literally as \"rotten pot\"?", "answer": "Potpourri", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c639", "question": "What does uranium become when it has lost all of its radioactivity?", "answer": "Lead", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea43b2ff048f679a45ab86", "question": "What is the largest kangaroo?", "answer": "The red kangaroo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0fb", "question": "Marvin Lee Aday is the real name of which well known singer?", "answer": "Meatloaf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26e", "question": "Who won an Oscar as Best Supporting actor in the 1993 film \"The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934c", "question": "What movie star was considered for the role of Dad in the TV show \"The Brady Bunch\"?", "answer": "Gene Hackman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4d", "question": "What year was Robert Downey Jr.'s first movie, \"Pound\" released in?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa9516ce05a3942286edf", "question": "What TV show inspired the F-16 combat plane nickname \"Viper\"?", "answer": "\"Battlestar Galactica\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b8", "question": "Who directed the 1980 movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "John Landis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b5a101dd7bf43be5e7d3", "question": "What is the term for the space between your eyebrows?", "answer": "Glabella", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca5", "question": "Who wrote the science-fiction novel \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a179", "question": "Which actor was \"The Postman\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5904a4c7cf93664eb10486c6", "question": "Shortly after meeting David, which North American city did Katchoo disappear to for 2 months, in the comic series \"Strangers in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d0", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was rich on Monday but broke on Sunday?", "answer": "Solomon Grundy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd0", "question": "What comedian has real-life twin sons named Matthew and Gregory?", "answer": "Ray Romano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339704", "question": "Which Star Trek character is a big fan of Earl Grey tea?", "answer": "Captain Picard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81b63d0de9af39e9d4678", "question": "Where did the deadliest avalanche occur?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a297", "question": "What was the name of Phil Collins' first solo album?", "answer": "Face Value", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961f", "question": "What actor played Bill the Butcher in the 2002 movie \"Gangs of New York\"?", "answer": "Daniel Day Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ccc", "question": "What Rhodes scholar and former Clinton advisor published the memoir \"All Too Human: A Political Education\" in 1999?", "answer": "George Stephanopolous", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c707", "question": "What large reptile gets its name from the Spanish meaning \"the lizard\"?", "answer": "Alligator", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133967b", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Springfield's retirement home?", "answer": "Springfield Retirement Castle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb9fa7e83c707845b2141", "question": "In the film \"The Shawshank Redemption,\" how long does Red spend in prison before being paroled?", "answer": "40 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e645fe83fe1f2a824bca", "question": "By what nickname is Edward Teach better known?", "answer": "The 17th century pirate \"Blackbeard\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e47", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"There's Something About Mary\"?", "answer": "Brett Favre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfe0058b668d7dfe168b5c1", "question": "How would the number 10 be expressed in binary notation?", "answer": "1010", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25a", "question": "What is 400 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "CD", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca5f", "question": "What is a kookaburra?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76f9eeec85e375820b2ec", "question": "The Atlantic Ocean Road links islands in what country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a1e1d75b5a031299b74573b", "question": "The Okapi is native to which African country?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e9", "question": "Jimmy McShane was the front man for which 1980's Italian new wave band?", "answer": "Baltimora", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5a", "question": "What president delivered his \"Fourteen Points\" speech in Congress in 1918?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339219", "question": "What actor is known as \"The Fonz\"?", "answer": "Henry Winkler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb734555e259d7869087328", "question": "Which US president went on record saying that he wished he could\u2019ve hanged his vice president during his administration?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ece", "question": "Achilles' heel was the result of him being dipped in what mythical river?", "answer": "The Styx", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "593c4c98b8198b9a2b07796a", "question": "In which city does Spider-Man live and protect?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d6552596a59cbdfbd3a9", "question": "What is the world's largest machine?", "answer": "The large hadron collider (LHC)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a96c", "question": "What is the only African country whose common name is only one syllable?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0be", "question": "In the traditional song, what did the children dance around \"on a cold and frosty morning\"?", "answer": "The mulberry bush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af53", "question": "During World War II, who was the \"Desert Fox\"?", "answer": "Field Marshall Rommell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77a", "question": "What large reptile was popularized by Steve Irwin and Paul Hogan?", "answer": "The crocodile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95a", "question": "What is another name for the starfruit?", "answer": "Carambola", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eef", "question": "According to its first line, in what city is the Band's song \"The Weight\" set?", "answer": "Nazareth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f6", "question": "Which character in the Simpsons was kicked out of the barbershop quartet, \"The Be Sharps\"?", "answer": "Chief Wiggum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071d013745b36be73039d3", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the V-2 rocket for Nazi Germany and later the Saturn V rocket for the United States?", "answer": "Wernher von Braun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a8", "question": "What is the middle color in a rainbow?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad32", "question": "What presidential daughter brought Socks the cat to the White House?", "answer": "Chelsea Clinton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5906820bff9c0647b50a8099", "question": "Who was the male lead in the 1976 film \"The Man Who Fell to Earth\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9e", "question": "What Ray Charles song was the basis for Kanye West's \"Gold Digger\"?", "answer": "I Got a Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2b", "question": "Who wrote \"De Profundis\" while in prison?", "answer": "Oscar Wilde", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5f", "question": "\"Typo\" is short for what two-word term?", "answer": "Typographical error", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab9", "question": "The \"Happy Days\" spin\u00adoff, \"Joanie Loves Chachi\", was set in which city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2cf", "question": "What is the oldest known vegetable?", "answer": "The pea", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd81", "question": "With what team did Dennis Rodman win his first NBA title?", "answer": "The Detroit Pistons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c58b", "question": "Lodgepole, Pinyon and Ponderosa are species of what plant?", "answer": "Pine tree", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45e", "question": "Which female gymnast won 3 golds and a silver at the 1972 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Olga Korbut", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d2", "question": "What was Murray Langston better known as to the public?", "answer": "The Unknown Comic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea77ccff048f679a45abcf", "question": "What is the name for a female fox?", "answer": "Vixen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d077c9870e6f05ba600867", "question": "What film starred Drew Barrymore, Mary-Louise Parker, and Matthew McConaughey?", "answer": "Boys on the Side", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58be2ca98faf425cf37add76", "question": "In what country would you find \"The Strand Arcade\", a covered shopping destination?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac6b", "question": "In 1923, which president started the National Christmas Tree Lighting Ceremony?", "answer": "Calvin Coolidge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ec", "question": "What was the name of Esther Rolles\u2019 character on both the TV shows \"Maude\" and \"Good Times\"?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd5d97e83c707845b2166", "question": "In which sport are the terms \"stale fish\" and \"mulekick\" used?", "answer": "Snowboarding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c499", "question": "Which English philosopher believed that people in a state of nature are good?", "answer": "John Locke", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a1", "question": "What sailor's disease resulted from a deficiency of Vitamin C?", "answer": "Scurvy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600242894be4723ccac22188", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Don Quixote\"?", "answer": "Miguel de Cervantes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04f", "question": "What was the only James Bond film to crack the top-ten list for highest grossing movies of the 1960s?", "answer": "Thunderball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339718", "question": "In which decade was Elvis Presley born?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4c", "question": "In what year was the Sony Corporation founded?", "answer": "1946", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdde", "question": "What fruit's name comes from the Nahuatl word for \"testicle\"?", "answer": "Avocado's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3231d3bf195a31e15d7388", "question": "Also known as the \"Chile Pine\", what is the common name of the tree \"Araucaria araucana\"?", "answer": "Monkey puzzle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b079", "question": "In 1996, what became the first minivan to be named Motor Trend magazine\u2019s \"Car of the Year\"?", "answer": "Dodge Caravan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d27", "question": "What children's books character is scared of Heffalumps and Woozles?", "answer": "Winnie the Pooh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26a", "question": "Who took Barry Goldwater's seat when the longtime senator retired in 1986?", "answer": "John McCain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6a1b46c0f9723ab15cb3d", "question": "Who was the first pope to visit the White House?", "answer": "Pope John Paul II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f4684af848b908361b876", "question": "As of 2020, what is the highest grossing film of all time without taking inflation into account?", "answer": "Avengers: Endgame", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa3", "question": "What does a philologist study?", "answer": "Languages", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51a51ff04d658268c9305", "question": "What philosophical tradition is associated with Jean-Paul Sartre?", "answer": "Existentialism", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990b047b72eedf883a8c710", "question": "Toxicodendron radicans, or T. radicans, is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "Poison Ivy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea7", "question": "What was the surname of Nicholas II, the last tsar of Russia?", "answer": "Romanov", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ca", "question": "Who sang the song \"Foolish Games\"?", "answer": "Jewel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a999b61d1b4d384d5d69d", "question": "Who portrayed Marshal Matt Dillon in the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "James Arness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062a58c9d816e292245c17", "question": "What is Judy Chicago's most well-known work?", "answer": "Regarded as the first epic feminist artwork, \"The Dinner Party\" functions as a symbolic history of women in Western civilization.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc5", "question": "How long is a fortnight?", "answer": "Two weeks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb4437e83c707845b2118", "question": "Water deer have what unique feature?", "answer": "Tusks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937eeec08d98002fdd633db", "question": "What is 2000 in Roman Numerals?", "answer": "MM", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e03", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Persephone?", "answer": "Proserpine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338898", "question": "What two girls do Archie and Reggie run around with?", "answer": "Betty and Veronica", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af70", "question": "Which US president was born in Milton, Massachusetts?", "answer": "George Bush Sr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b5749076251badbeac3", "question": "For what does NAACP stand?", "answer": "National Association for the Advancement of Colored People", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c744", "question": "What is the more common name for the bone called the furcula, found in birds?", "answer": "Wishbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d21", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Days of Thunder\"?", "answer": "Car racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ac", "question": "What city is often mistakenly referred to as the \"Lost City of the Incas\"?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ae", "question": "What is the capitol of Morocco?", "answer": "Rabat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee7", "question": "What year was the Commodore 64 first released?", "answer": "1982", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65973ae7e414034b5aeff", "question": "What was the first European country to allow women to vote?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8fd3701dd7bf43be5e85b", "question": "On the internet, what does Yahoo! stand for?", "answer": "Yet Another Hierarchical Organized Oracle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae93e4574a5ce6b56b8240", "question": "Who's the lead singer of the band \"Simply Red\"?", "answer": "Mick Hucknall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c048", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of India?", "answer": "Indian Peacock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7dfbff048f679a45ac04", "question": "Arithmophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Numbers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e0e", "question": "What was the first decade revisited by VH-1's \"I Love the...\" series?", "answer": "1980s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39a", "question": "What year was the American Red Cross founded?", "answer": "1881", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a443", "question": "What river does the Tower Bridge in London cross?", "answer": "Thames", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600242374be4723ccac22182", "question": "Which leading English poet of was killed in action during World War I one week before the end of the war?", "answer": "Wilfred Owen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb53", "question": "How deep is each end zone on a CFL football field?", "answer": "20 yards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69aab20565ad31a57c756", "question": "In the Bible, who is the wife of Boaz?", "answer": "Ruth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5901dbe5709c1c34536e6eb3", "question": "With what artist did Kid Rock record the song titled \"Picture\"?", "answer": "Sheryl Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf9a", "question": "In the standard game of Scrabble, what is the value of the letters \"Q\" and \"Z\"?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f16", "question": "What author created Neverland?", "answer": "J. M. Barrie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af06", "question": "President Gerald Ford was a member of which political party?", "answer": "Republican Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339282", "question": "In season 14 of \"Big Brother\" what coach told Britney that she is so good because she is incapable of feeling emotion?", "answer": "Janelle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338874", "question": "What Emily Bronte novel features Heathcliff?", "answer": "Wuthering Heights", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c809", "question": "How many pairs of chromosomes are there in each human cell?", "answer": "23", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ba", "question": "Which US state is directly south of Georgia?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a98a561d1b4d384d5d68f", "question": "On which family does the TV show \"Bonanza\" center on?", "answer": "Cartwright", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd3e0ec223966ae8f88c9", "question": "Which superhero does Mark Watney emulate near the end of \"The Martian\"?", "answer": "Iron Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f13", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Cate Blanchett and Judi Dench?", "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bd05b7e40191c55fd523fb2", "question": "What horror game created more fear of animatronics?", "answer": "Five Nights At Freddy's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c296", "question": "Who oversaw the design and assembly of the first atomic bomb?", "answer": "J. Robert Oppenheimer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ea", "question": "\"The 10 days that shook the world\" refers to what country\u2019s revolution?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace9", "question": "What Harvard dropout held 535 US patents upon his death in 1991, second only to Thomas Edison?", "answer": "Edwin Land", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69d0920565ad31a57c773", "question": "Mikhail Gorbachev informally agreed to help Ronald Reagan and the U.S. in the event of what situation?", "answer": "UFO invasion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389ac", "question": "What children's book hero did the cruel Dursleys bring up after an evil wizard killed his parents?", "answer": "Harry Potter", "category": "arts"}]